

# Kayahan Kaya

Helmond, 5708ZK, Netherlands | +31629218155

kayahankaya@icloud.com | www.linkedin.com/in/kayahankaya | http://kayakayahan.com

Born on June 9, 1991.

Mechanical Engineer with 6 years of process engineering and technical project experience in multiple engineering disciplines, primarily in the Automotive Manufacturing Industry as a Feasibility and Process Engineer.

(I have a valid residence and work permit in the Netherlands, so I do not require visa sponsorship.)

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Process and Feasibility Engineer**

Apr 2019 - Jan 2022

Ford Motor Company, Kocaeli, Turkey

Design and Manufacturing Integration:

- Reviewed design concepts to ensure alignment with function and standards and ensure highquality tool designs.
- Collaborated with Design leader, Program Manager, and/or Product Designer to identify necessary changes to tool designs in support of product changes.
- Followed tools through buy-off, providing feedback and support as needed.

#### Professional Development and Continuous Improvement:

- Contributed to departmental process improvements for future projects.
- Drove continuous improvements to enhance manufacturability, quality, and cost-effectiveness.
- Collaborated with suppliers and manufacturing partners to resolve technical issues.
- Provided technical guidance and mentorship to junior engineers, contributing to the professional development of the engineering team.

### Main Commercial Vehicle Projects:

- Completed three major commercial vehicle projects, including V713, V710, and V763.
- Main feasibility scope focused on core panels, including front door outer, front door inner, roofs, hood outer/inner, and other panels (15 panels/process involving 55 dies/operations).

### Feasibility and Design Support:

- Provided stamping feasibility feedback and proposed solutions to Design Studio and Product Development Teams for Ford Otosan, Ford of Europe, and Ford North America in new vehicle projects.
- Checked part designs according to Process Driven Product Design (PDPD) to offer quick feedback to the Product Design Team during the feasibility phase (Created 'Roof Panels PDPD' for an internal know-how database).
- Created process concepts and determined process parameters for each part in alignment with Main and Alternative Press Lines, following Global Press Book guidelines, and coordinated with relevant teams (Die Design, Die Manufacturing, Press Shop) through set meetings for each panel.

### Cost Optimization and Tooling Support:

- Generated cost reduction ideas, including "Die number optimization" and "Material Utilization Percentage."
- Provided subject matter expertise and supported tooling suppliers, resulting in cost savings (e.g., saved 1 die cost and 7€ for each vehicle for Front Door Inner part of V763 project and 1-5€ for each part of roof panels in V710 project).

### Project Leadership and Problem Solving:

- Led the Stamping Feasibility Period of new vehicle projects by fostering collaborative teamwork between Product Development, Design Studio, Die Process Teams, and outsources.
- Defined design-based problems and proposed solutions applicable to vehicle design, resolving over 600 design-based issues based on FCR's report.

Product Development and Compliance:

- · Transformed product concepts into feasible, reliable, and cost-effective engineering solutions.
- Ensured that products/solutions complied with applicable laws, regulations, and industry standards.
- Released finished products in BOMs and detailed production, assembly, and/or inspection documentation.

Product Validation and Engineering Analysis:

- Set up and executed product validation procedures for the projects worked on.
- Possessed experience with systematic, proactive methods for evaluating product concepts and processes, including FMEA, DFA, DFM, and static/dynamic strength analyses.

Skills: Product Data Management (PDM), Geometric Dimensioning, Tolerancing, CATIA, Mechanical Drawings, Metalworking, Analytical Skills, Manufacturing Processes, Process Design, Automotive, Mechanical Product Design, Product Development, Modeling and Simulation, Manufacturing Process Improvement, Technical Drawing, Process Optimization, Tooling Design, Teamcenter, Production Processes, Engineering Design, Computer-Aided Engineering (CAE), Design Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, Problem Solving, 3D Computer-Aided Design (3D CAD), Finite Element Analysis (FEA), Design for Manufacturing, CAD, Project Management, Cost Reduction, PLM (Product Lifecycle Management), Six Sigma, FMEA, Production Tools, Quality Requirements, Statistical Process Control, Lean Manufacturing, Prepare Technical Documentation, Supplier Relationship Management, Risk Management, Quality Control (QC).

### **Technical Support - Project Engineer**

Sep 2016 - Apr 2019

Vaillant Group, Turkey

- Performing over 90 field visits annually for initial customer contact and site surveys, including service centers, dealers, and commercial customers.
- Coordinating and collaborating with project team members, including Customer Services, Supply Chain Management, Sales & Marketing, Quality Management, suppliers, subcontractors, and more, to support dealers and after-sales services by creating projects for related HVAC equipments.
- Collaborating with the sales team for direct customers, identifying tender requirements and customer needs.
- Defining and implementing technical training strategies for all internal and external customers, including a staff of over 1000 dealers.
- Providing technical support to all internal and external customers across the full product portfolio, including 302 large-scale HVAC project designs.
- Managing the customer complaint process to ensure the provision of solutions for customer problems that could not be solved by other departments, ensuring end-user complaints are resolved in a timely manner.
- Providing support for After-Sales Service and Complaint Management to find technical solutions for end-user problems and ensuring complaints are managed in a professional manner, including creating a database of CAD drawings for basic solutions.

**Skills:** Contact Management, Layout Design for Heating Systems, CAD, Project Management, Project Planning, Mechanical Drawings, Analytical Skills, Process Design, Communication, Calculations, Technical Drawing, Problem Solving, AutoCAD, Data Analysis, Team Collaboration, Quality Assurance (QA), Innovative Problem Solving, Technical Training, Troubleshooting.

# Technical Support Engineer

Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

3bFab, Turkey

- Planning Technical Support appointments through Salesforce and installing our 3D Printing and 3D Scanning machines for customers.
- Providing technical support both on-site and at the company. Following the solutions of technical
  cases coming from customers via email, telephone, or the sales team.
- Making daily task distributions within the team. Solving malfunctions and customer complaints by telephone and email.
- Periodically organizing advanced training seminars for all devices purchased by customers.
- Performing periodic and corrective maintenance of systems at the customer site.
- Traveling internationally to visit customers. Acting as the ambassador at the customer site.
- Detecting and solving malfunctions and complaints related to electronics, mechanics, pneumatics, software, and process technical parameters.
- Providing detailed reports of field issues for new products in the field.
- Reporting structural issues and findings for improvement and preparing service reports.
- Repairing systems and spare parts in our workshop and keeping machine lists up to date.

**Skills:** Rapid Prototyping, SLA, FDM, Hands-on Installations, Knowledge Center Management, Geometric Dimensioning & Tolerancing, Analytical Skills, Technical Support, Communication, 3D Modeling, Mechanical Product Design, Prototyping, Engineering Design, Autodesk Inventor, Design Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, Problem Solving, 3D Computer-Aided Design (CAD), SolidWorks, 3D Printing, Additive Manufacturing, Continuous Improvement, Operational Efficiency, Formlabs, Ultimaker, Makerbot.

### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) - Mechanical Engineering

Sep 2009 - Dec 2015

Yildiz Technical University, Istanbul

### **High School Diploma - Science**

Sep 2005 - Jun 2009

Bornova Anadolu Lisesi, Izmir

### **SKILLS**

Languages: Turkish (Native), English (Professional)

**Soft Skills:** Prioritization, Communication, Initiative, Ownership, Quick Learning, Innovation, Determination, Self-Driven, Collaboration, Presentation, Listening, Adaptability (Open to Change), Time Management, Deadline Adherence, Decision-Making, Attention to Detail, Precision, Forward-Thinking, Risk Management, Stakeholder Management, Conflict Resolution

**Expert in:** Python, Catia V5 (Surface Modelling), AutoForm **Intermediate in:** SQL, MySQL, SolidWorks, AutoCAD

Basic in: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, Software Development, Web Development, Tkinter, Django, Numpy,

Pandas, TensorFlow, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn, PyTorch, R, Teamcenter

#### **HOBBIES**

Football, Canoeing, Board gaming, Running, Camping

#### **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

Python Programming Language C and System Programmers Association	2023
Git and GitHub Bootcamp Colt Steele	2023
Statistics for Data Science  Udemy	2022
Introduction to SQL Data Science School	2022
Introduction to Programming Cenk Sener	2022
Process Designer Ford Motor Company	2020
Catia V5 (Advance Surface Modelling) Grup Otomasyon PLM	2019
Catia V5 Grup Otomasyon PLM	2019
AutoForm Grup Otomasyon PLM	2019
SolidWorks Yildiz Technical University	2015
AutoCAD Bemka Kariyer	2012